Go!
Hit him!
Finish him!
Hop in now.
Na-mu, are you allowed to drive?
I got my license last week for this day.
Get in already.
Let's call the police.
Uncle told me to do so when in trouble.
Hold on. What if they arrest him too?
That can't happen.
He shouldn't be arrested!
That place is full of bad people.
What do we do if something happens?
Who are you calling?
Hello? This is Han Geu-ru.
You told me to call you
if something bad happens.
Something bad is happening to me now!
Here!
Right.
We need the passcode to get in.
What shall we do?
Darn it.
What?
What are you doing?
What the…?
How did you know?
I saw the numbers
when I came to find Uncle.
What? You came here to find him?
With whom?
With whom did you come here?
He's over there.
No! He's already in a fight.
Hit him!
Uncle!
Darn it.
Shit.
Turn the darn lights on!
Over there!
What?
Where are you going?
Get up already!
Get up!
Fight back!
What's going on?
Turn back the lights on!
What's going on here?
Uncle.
What? What are you doing here?
Let's get out of here.
Hey! What the heck are you doing?
What the hell are you doing?
-What?
-What is it?
What is it?
The police!
It's the police!
The police is here!
Run, everyone!
Now, you are all under arrest
for illegal gambling.
You have the right to have an attorney
to defend yourself.
You also have the right to refuse…
SWAT TEAM
What happened?
How did you find me here?
Punch drunk syndrome.
We know you have it.
"Punch drunk"?
You must go to a hospital.
Your head might explode.
You can't die!
-You can't die!
-Geu-ru!
You got it wrong.
I'm not dying!
Your uncle is fine,
so calm down.
I don't believe you.
Let's go to a hospital.
I'm telling you.
I don't have punch drunk syndrome.
Move.
-Okay.
-Don't push me.
The place was so well hidden
that we were fooled every time.
How did you find out?
I have an informant.
-An informant?
-Come on!
Who is it?
Well, that's…
confidential.
What the fuck?
Come on!
What's this?
Get in!
MOVE TO HEAVEN
No.
Don't.
Don't!
No!
Oh shit!
What the…?
What are you doing here?
I'm here
to check if you are still alive.
Hey.
I told you.
I'm fine.
Even the doctor said last night
I'll be fine if I'm careful from now on.
I'm in the hospital
because you guys insisted,
but they say I'm good to go even now.
Is it true?
Yes, it's true.
Dad kept the truth of his illness from me.
That's because
your dad loved you so much
that he didn't want you to be worried.
I don't love you that much.
So I'm not hiding anything.
Then it's all good.
That's wonderful.
Don't love me, Uncle.
Don't hide any truth from me.
Sleepy?
See? You should've stayed home.
Why bothered to come?
Can I sleep here?
Sure, why not?
Shoot.
The Seoul Metropolitan Police
and Nambu Prosecutors' Office
announced that on the night of the 9th,
the authorities rounded up a group
running a gambling den
where unauthorized fights were conducted
with billions of won at stake.
Here's the investigation report
of the Public Prosecutors' Office.
Around midnight on the 9th,
the Seoul Metropolitan Police
and the Nambu Prosecutors' office
received a tip-off of a big gambling den
where fights were being conducted
with billions at stake.
We mobilized immediately and arrested
most of the individuals related
to the crime--
-Uncle, breakfast is ready.
-For me?
You prepared for me too?
I can sit there?
-Thank you for the food.
Mr. Oh, what brings you here this early?
I'm here to talk to Geu-ru.
Geu-ru,
how long will you keep
your dad's ashes here?
The memorial park told me
they've been calling you
about his natural burial
which is ready now.
They say that you've been avoiding
their calls and texts.
I know how heartbroken you are,
but it's time to let him go.
Let him rest beside your mom
before it's too late.
Hey.
Geu-ru.
Gosh.
Geu-ru!
You've been there for hours!
Please come out.
Geu-ru,
are you going to stay there forever?
Geu-ru, aren't you hungry?
Don't you need to go to the bathroom?
He's so stubborn.
He hasn't had water for over 12 hours.
Goodness.
Oh, no! Is he dehydrated?
What if he fainted?
What?
Geu-ru!
Answer me!
Shoot. That's it. Move aside.
Geu-ru!
Is he only invisible to me?
Look.
What?
This crazy punk!
Next door, where did he go?
How would I know?
I can't believe this kid.
Hold on. First off,
we need to figure out where he might be.
Geu-ru!
Han Geu-ru!
-How did it go?
-Not good.
-Where on earth did he go?
-Goodness.
Han Geu-ru!
Geu-ru!
Shit.
It's driving me nuts.
Han Geu-ru!
Gosh.
Where did he go?
Goodness.
Han Jeong-u,
your son is missing.
I want to find him, but
I don't know anything
about your son.
I have no clue what to do now.
Don't just stand there and smile.
Say something!
Darn it.
What the heck am I doing?
Darn.
The test results show no abnormalities
in his hearing or vocal organs.
Then why doesn't he speak?
In this case,
we can assume it stems from
his unusual psychological state.
He doesn't want to speak for some reason.
We call this selective mutism.
Then what can we do?
We have to wait for now.
Let's find another way
to communicate with him.
Your facial expressions and body gestures
are very important.
"Thank you."
"I appreciate it."
RED SKATE, WHITE-SPOTTED EAGLE RAY
What about "I'm sorry"?
Jeong-u, how do we say,
"It's dangerous. Don't touch it"?
I can't remember. One moment.
"I'm sorry"…
When we say "I'm sorry"…
Jeong-u, you need to see this.
What?
Geu-ru.
Can you show your dad how to say,
"It's dangerous. Don't touch it"?
Okay. One more time.
"I'm sorry."
It's our first time here, Geu-ru.
Look at the group of fish coming this way.
Wow, look over there!
There are so many.
-He likes it here.
-Right.
Geu-ru.
Do you like it here?
The fish are fantastic, aren't they?
Butterfly ray.
Butterfly ray
belongs to Gymnuridae, Rajiformes,
Chondrichthyes, Chordata, Animalia.
It is one meter long.
Its large and flat body disc is overall
in a diamond shape
with its body and head joined together
with the pectoral fins.
-The front tip is pointed…
-Geu-ru is finally…
…in a soft S-shape.
-It's wider than its length.
-Thank you, Lord. Thank you so much.
BUSAN FIREFIGHTING SERVICE
BEST FIREFIGHTER KIM JUN-SIK
BUSAN FIRE DEPARTMENT, 2011
SENIOR FIREFIGHTER HAN JEONG-U, 2000
AWARDED FIREFIGHTER OF THE MONTH
BUSAN FIRE DEPARTMENT, APRIL 2000
Are you the one asking about Han Jeong-u?
Yes, the kid's name is Han Geu-ru, right?
You still remember him.
How old is he now?
He's 20.
That means 20 years have passed already.
Do you know about Geu-ru?
Is he…
Do you want to know how Jeong-u met him?
Yes.
Everyone with him that day says
they can never forget what happened.
It snowed here that day.
As you know, we rarely have snow here
even in the middle of winter.
It was a really clear day,
but suddenly something like dust
was falling from the sky.
It was snow.
Hey, guys, come out! It's snowing now!
Can't you see it's snowing?
Wow.
-It's snowing a lot!
-This is awesome.
-It's my first snow here.
-Really?
-Yes, since I came here.
He's a country bumpkin.
Snow in Busan? Unbelievable.
119 FIRE DEPARTMENT
Gosh, let's go.
They think a cat is trapped
in the water tank in Seongmun-dong.
Someone made a complaint
about losing sleep because of its noise.
It's a cat again.
It crawled into the tank to get warm,
then it got trapped there.
Are we the 911 rescue team,
or animal rescuers?
We are cat rescuers for sure.
Be ready.
911 RESCUE
Hello.
This way?
Where is the cat?
Where are you going?
Is it here?
-Here's the cage.
-Okay.
A cat's meow sounds like a baby's crying.
It gives me the creeps.
Darn it.
What are you waiting for?
Get the equipment now.
-Yes, sir.
-It's snowing. Move your lazy ass.
-Hurry!
-Jun-sik!
What?
Listen.
Listen carefully.
Oh no.
I hear nothing now. Is it dead?
-Hold it. One, two, three!
-One, two, three!
Kitty.
Kitty, where are you?
Kitty!
Kitty.
Call the ambulance now!
We got a baby down here!
It's not a cat. It's a human baby!
It's a baby!
EMERGENCY RESPONSE
Hurry.
How can this be?
Go now.
NEONATAL INTENSIVE CARE UNIT
Excuse me.
What happened to the baby
rescued from the water tank today?
Are you the firefighter who rescued him?
Yes. How is he?
Not good.
He was in a place like that
in this weather.
He's way too young for that.
It's too early to lose hope.
It's a miracle he managed to survive
in that condition.
RESTRICTED AREA, NO CELL PHONES
Would you like to see him?
Can I?
Live.
You can make it.
Fight back.
Jeong-u.
The baby from the tank.
Yes, what about him?
I heard he made a recovery.
Something's wrong?
No, he'll be sent to an agency.
We should report on the situation
at the time he was found.
I wrote up everything.
You can just sign it.
Which agency?
The ward office said since he's a baby,
he might be adopted overseas
or something like that.
What's up?
Do you remember that baby
I rescued from the water tank?
Yes.
Is he not doing good?
No, he's all recovered.
He'll be sent to an agency.
And he might be
sent away for overseas adoption.
Babies are still sent away like that
even now.
I guess so.
-Jeong-u.
-Yes?
I want to see that baby.
Really?
Yes.
Hey.
-Wow.
-Goodness.
That's right.
Look how gentle he is.
Right?
He has a stronger grip now.
This is amazing.
Wow.
You're eating well.
Is it good?
There, there.
It's all right. What's that?
Hey.
Hey. There, there.
Goodness.
It's okay. It's all right.
Jeong-u!
What should we do?
What is it? What's wrong?
The baby
will be adopted soon.
Jeong-u.
I can't let him go.
I don't think I can.
-What do I do now?
-What do you think?
If you can't let him go,
we don't have to.
Are you sure?
I was going to bring it up if you didn't.
I already have a name for him.
Jeong-u!
Wait,
you named the baby?
Without discussing it with me?
What did you name him?
Geu-ru.
Han Geu-ru!
Why? You don't like it?
No.
I love it.
Han Geu-ru.
Our son's name.
What a wonderful name.
Couples tend to resemble each other,
but they were more than that.
They were so alike
as if they were one person split into two.
Look over there.
Okay, here.
One, two, three!
Geu-ru was so adorable
and became our mascot here.
Good job.
Why did Jeong-u quit the job here
and moved to Seoul?
They were so happy,
but with the good comes with bad,
his wife became ill.
She was always weak. Maybe that's why.
As soon as she was diagnosed
with terminal cancer,
she refused the treatment
to spend time with her son.
Jeong-u quit the job right away,
and his family spent every moment together
till she was gone.
Mom is crying.
Mom is sick.
No.
These are happy tears.
What is "happy"?
It's like you feel really good.
It makes you smile.
Being happy makes
water come out of your eyes.
I am happy
whenever I see you.
Water comes out of your eyes
whenever you see me.
Geu-ru.
Thank you
for letting me live as your mom.
Thank you so much.
A lot of "happy" is coming out now.
LEARNING THE KOREAN ALPHABET
You need to stop.
Mom isn't here anymore.
Mom is here!
BEAUTIFUL AND HAPPY CITY BUSAN
Oh, maybe he went there.
-Sorry?
-If he came here,
he had only one place to go.
Where is it?
Geu-ru, let's go see mom.
Mom is not here.
Mom is here.
Where?
Right here
and here.
And
right here too.
Geu-ru.
Close your eyes.
Do you remember
we came here often with Mom?
I can see mom.
Mom, Dad, and I
are all here.
No.
I don't like it.
Please come back.
Come back quickly.
Come now.
No!
I don't like it!
-Geu-ru.
-I don't like it!
-Geu-ru!
-No, please come back!
Geu-ru.
Geu-ru!
Dad is gone.
I can't see him anymore.
Yes.
I miss my dad.
But I can't see him anymore.
No matter how hard I try,
Dad doesn't give me a prize,
"Excellent job."
I can't hear his voice anymore too.
Really?
I don't think that's true.
Someone I know told me
that even the deceased
can speak.
MOVE TO HEAVEN
Mr. Han Jeong-u,
on April 13th, 2020,
you passed away.
I'm Han Geu-ru, a trauma cleaner
from Move to Heaven.
Now,
I will begin
to help you with your final move.
EXCELLENT JOB, COMPLIMENTS FOR HAN GEU-RU
NAME: HAN GEU-RU, EXCELLENT JOB
AWARD
SENIOR FIREFIGHTER HAN JEONG-U
HAPPY FIRST BIRTHDAY, GEU-RU
FRIDAY, APRIL 20TH, 2001
GEU-RU, HAN GEU-RU,
MONDAY, APRIL 30TH, 2001
MOVE TO HEAVEN
GALLERY
That was awkward. Again.
Son.
Geu-ru.
When it's time to say goodbye,
people cannot lie.
Do you remember
what your mom's last word is?
Thank you
for letting me live as your mom.
Thank you so much.
If someone asked me
what my happiest memories in life were,
I'd answer they were living as your dad.
You are sad
because you can't see me, aren't you?
But Geu-ru,
you can't ever forget what you see.
Memories about Mom and Dad are
all saved in your eyes.
So I'm sure you will be fine, right?
Okay, lastly,
you have to promise me one thing.
Remember what I told you everyday?
From now on,
you will be telling that
to yourself in the mirror everyday
in my place.
What did I say?
"Excellent job."
That's right.
Yes, excellent job, my son.
-Who's the coolest person in the world?
-Han Jeong-u's son, Han Geu-ru.
THE LATE HAN JEONG-U, REST IN PEACE
THE LATE HAN JEONG-U, 1977-2020
THE LATE MIN JI-WON,1977-2006
That's right.
Talking with people
is difficult.
I can't understand
what's on people's minds.
When you want to get
their feelings and thoughts,
you can imagine yourself
being in their shoes.
I can't do that because I'm not them.
It's easy. Just imagine.
"How sad would I be if I were that sick?"
"How mad would I be
if someone lied to me?"
"How happy would I be
if someone said nice things to me?"
Like that.
Don't get nervous.
Just let it know
you don't hate it or aren't intimidated.
See?
Nothing happens.
No.
-Oh no, Geu-ru!
-Na-mu.
HAN JEONG-U
What did I always say to you?
Although you can't see someone…
"It doesn't mean they're not with me."
As long as you remember…
"They are not gone."
That's right.
-Mr. Cho.
-Yes?
You've done a great job.
Oh, no problem.
Today is the last day
of those three months we promised.
As the supervisor
of Geu-ru's guardianship,
for three months,
I've closely watched
how you got along with him,
and I've made a decision
whether it's okay
for you to maintain your guardianship.
I have decided
that you're disqualified
to be Geu-ru's guardian.
There are many reasons,
but the biggest one is
the illegal gambling incident.
Your involvement
in that group's illegal acts
put Geu-ru in danger.
Would you like to elaborate on anything?
No, I wouldn't.
Then you don't object
if I demand to terminate
your guardianship contract
with Gue-ru, do you?
No, I don't.
Then what's going to happen to him?
Are you worried about him?
No.
I'm not worried at all.
That kid has you
and Next door, so I'm not worried.
I feel much relieved now.
I never thought
of being a guardian or protector before,
so this job was such a hassle.
So I would've said no
even if you asked me to keep doing it.
It's good news.
I guess this is it.
I should get going.
Thank you.
Where are you going?
We are not done yet.
That was purely my opinion.
Geu-ru has expressed that
he'd like to continue to have you
as his guardian.
Sorry?
The ward's opinion
is the most important factor
when it comes
to the guardianship contract.
Therefore, you, Mr. Cho,
are still and will continue to be
Geu-ru's guardian.
Any objections?
Goodness.
-Do you hear what you're saying?
-Stop throwing stuff!
Stop what?
Say it again! What did you just say?
Keep asking me won't change my answer.
I will no longer hide from you,
and I'll say it out loud.
I'm officially going to work with Geu-ru
at Move to Heaven!
Are you out of your mind?
Stop right there!
I can't believe her!
Why did I give birth to that brat?
Gosh, she's driving me crazy!
I've always known this day would come.
What?
From the day Geu-ru and his dad
came by to say hi when they moved in.
From the moment I heard
the boy of Na-mu's age
was named Han Geu-ru.
So what about it?
Na-mu, a tree, Han Geu-ru, one tree!
Even their names are meant to be.
We'll have to give in.
There's no way
parents can change their child's destiny.
Destiny, my foot!
I will get her name changed right away!
Na-mu? Han Geu-ru? That's ridiculous!
Excuse me.
Is this Move to Heaven,
a trauma cleaning company
for dead people?
-Yes.
-Hi.
Nice to meet you.
How can I help you?
I came here to make a request
for trauma cleaning.
When did the deceased pass away?
She hasn't passed away yet.
But she's going to soon.
Okay.
Then,
give me the name and address
of the deceased-to-be
with the name and number
of the one who requests.
The name of the deceased-to-be
is Cha Eun-byeol.
Her address is 358-4, Yeonhwa-dong, Seoul.
And the one who requests the service is
also Cha Eun-byeol.
That's odd.
What is odd?
The deceased-to-be and the client
has the same name.
It's not odd at all.
Because I'm going to die soon,
I'm requesting the service for myself.
Subtitle translation by: Jean S Kim